Does the structure of coalition building, in your opinion, help to balance the exhaustive effort of organizing at all?
Because I think theoretically it is.
But then it's like, yeah, but then you end up having to manage more people, which is exhausting.
Yeah.
So me and David, we talk about this all the time.
So that's why we're over here grinning and smiling at each other.
I'm just like, eh.
So the short answer is right.
Like the coalition building is how you build power.
It is how you get transformative things done.
And there is a lot of difficulty in managing, you know, coalitions and working in coalition as well.
Because especially when we're talking about our people who have been traumatized and impacted by white supremacy, capitalism and all these, you know, isms.
We come into the work with certain traumas, with certain, you know, issues that show up in our relationships with one another.
So I think that the short answer is the coalition work does make it easier.
You're able to spread the work if you, you know, have effective and healthy coalitions.
But there is also additional labor required to make sure that you are in healthy relationship with one another as you are working on your particular initiative or campaign.
So that means, like, really leaning into actually building relationships.
Like, you cannot just bring random sets of people together and expect that you are going to be able to work together effectively.
Like, you've got to build relationships, get to know one another, do the one-on-ones, you know, make space to have fun with each other because, you know.
So y'all doing retreats? Y'all doing trust falls and things like this?
Yes, absolutely.
Basically.
Like the flag.
Okay.
Yeah.
Better.
Absolutely.
All that to say is it's necessary.
It's super important.
And coalition work is extremely difficult.
Well, if you ever, if you ever want me to come and do some stand-up at the beginning of one of your retreats to loosen the floor, let me know.
Yeah, we might need that.
My favorite song is, First I Was Afraid.
I was petrified.
Okay.